Guide to the Southern Feminist, Inc. records, 1975-1990. RL.11828
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Southern Feminist, Inc. records
1975-1990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Southern Feminist, Inc.
Hannon, Sharron
RL.11828
5.5 Linear Feet
Southern Feminist, Inc. was an organization in Athens, GA from 1984-1989 that served as a communications device for women's political activism in the southern states. Their records consist chiefly of administrative files, which includes correspondence, article drafts, and subscription information. Also included is a group of feminist periodicals including Southern Feminist.
Arrangement
The original filing system has been kept intact.
Biographical / Historical
Southern Feminist, Inc. was an Athens, GA organization that served as a communication device for women's political activism in the southern states from 1984-1989.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Southern Feminist, Inc. records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1990.
Collection Overview
The collection includes the records of the periodical The Southern Feminist, which was founded by editor and publisher Sharron Hannon in Athens.The records of Southern Feminist Inc. chiefly consist of sdministrative files, such as correspondence, drafts of articles, subscription files. Printed materials are mostly feminist peridocals and include issues of The Southern Feminist and The Southern Feminist Extra.
Women's periodicals, American. -- Southern States; Equality before the law -- United States; Women -- Political activity -- Southern States; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Administrative Files, 1982-1988
  - Advertisements, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advertising, 1982-1986 and undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arts, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Book Reviews, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Business Information, 1976-1985 and undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Classifieds, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Guidelines for Contributors, 1984 and undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Copyrights, 1984 and undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Editorials, 1984, June-November (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Graphics, 1982-1987 and undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Layouts, 1984-1985 and undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Mailings, 1982-1984 and undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Marketing, 1987 and undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Networks, 1984 and undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Promotions, 1983-1987 and undated; 2 folders (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Public Relations, 1984-1986 and undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Story Ideas, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subscriptions, 1984-1985 and undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Surveys, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Women's Sports, 1982-1985; 2 folders (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1987; 2 folders (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Direct Mail, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Features, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Finances, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - First Person, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Health and Fitness, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Herstory, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Letters, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - News Briefs, 1983-1984 and undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - News Makers, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Opinion and Comment, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Arts, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Books, 1985-1988; 2 folders (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
  - Cartoons, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Coming Events, 1986-1987; 2 folders (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Features, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - First Person, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Health and Fitness, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Letters, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - May Extra, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Media, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - News, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - On Campus, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Opinion and Commentary, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Organizing, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Special Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Working, 1986-1987 and undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Politics, 1981-1987; 16 folders
    - Politics, 1986-1987; 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
    - Alabama, 1983-1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Arkansas, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Florida, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Kentucky, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Louisiana, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mississippi, 1982-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - North Carolina, 1981-1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - South Carolina, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Tennessee, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Texas, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Virginia, 1981-1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Politics and Government, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Quotes, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Relationships, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Printed Material, 1983-1990
  - Atlanta Woman, 1983 (December) - 1984 (July) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Conscience, 1985 (May) - 1990 (December); 2 folders (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - Feminist Connection, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 8, Box 9)
  - Network, 1983, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 9, Box 9)
  - Hersay, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - On the Issues, 1984-1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Southern Feminist and Southern Feminist Extra, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 2, Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous including brochures, 1975-1990 and undated; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 3-5, Box 9)